Kono omoi wo keshite shimau niwa
mada jinsei nagai dsho?
Yarinokoshite'ru koto
yarinaoshite mitai kara
Yume no tsuzuki oikakete ita hazu na no ni
Magarikunetta
hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
Ano koro mitai ni tte modoritai wake ja nai ni
Nakushite kita sora wo sagashite'ru
Wakatte kuremasu you ni
Gisei ni natta you na
kanashii kao wa yamete yo
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
Zutto kurushiku seotte'ku n da
Deguchi mienai kanjou meiro ni
dare wo matte'ru no?
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta you ni
motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
Nani kar nogaretai n da
genjitsu tte yatsu?
Kanaeru tame ni ikite'ru n datte
Sakebitaku naru yo Kikoete imasu ka?
Bunai n nante yatte'rarenai kara
...kaeru basho mo nai no
Yasashisa niwa itsumo kansha shite'ru
Dakara tsuyoku naritai
(I'm on the way)
Natsukashiku naru
konna itami mo kangei jan
In search of the dark secrets
of the Philosopher's Stone,
Ed and Al break into the
supposedly deserted Fifth Laboratory.
There they encounter
two guards who, like Al,
have had their souls
bonded to suits of armor.
In the course of their fight, Al's
opponent, 66, plants suspicions in his mind.
Al begins to wonder if he is a
counterfeit soul created by Ed,
and bonded to a suit of armor to
become the older boy's biddable puppet.
ROSS: Looks like you can sit up now, huh?
[CRICKETS CHIRPING]
What happened with the Fifth Laboratory?
Well, it, um...
Somebody blew up the building and
there's nothing left of it now but rubble.
Damn it!
You mean they wiped out everything?
That didn't feel good.
This isn't fair...
Do you know how close I
was to finding out the truth?
This is no time for me to
be lying around in a hospital.
BOTH: Hm.
BOTH: Fullmetal Alchemist, sir!
Hm?
We do apologize in advance for this!
Huh?
[SMACK]
You acted like a selfish child.
You only escaped with your
life because you were lucky.
You don't have to do everything
all on your own, you know.
You can lean on other people.
Like us.
Not all adults are the enemy.
You can trust us.
BOTH: That's all!
Please forgive our abusive
words and conduct, sir!
It will not happen again!
Uh...
No, you're right.
I should be apologizing.
My punishment...
for slapping you.
Huh?
Nothing, I had it coming.
[RELIEVED SOUNDS]
What's got you two so scared of me?
- State-certified alchemists carry a military rank equivalent to that of a Major.
- Mm-hmm.
Don't worry about it.
I didn't get my certification
so people would kiss up to me.
You don't have to talk to me
like I'm a high-ranking officer.
Really? Oh!
Ah, I guess we were
scared of the brat for nothing.
They adjust quickly...
Um, where's Al? I haven't seen him.
Alphonse got his own lecture earlier.
But I was the one who did the slapping.
[PAINED LAUGHTER]
I almost forgot.
I have an even less pleasant
lecture in store for me today.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello? Rockbell Prosthetic Glam Outfitters.
Oh, Ed.
Since when do you ever bother to call us, is something wrong?
Yeah...
Here's the deal.
I hate to ask you, but...do you think you
could make a service call out to Central for me?
A service call?
Yeah.
My right arm's messed up again.
I can move the fingers,
but that's about it.
I can't lift the arm at all.
[GASPS]
[NERVOUS LAUGH]
- Yeah, that sounds about right.
- Huh?
Nothing! Just talking to myself.
So, what were you doing
when the arm stopped working?
Uh... [GULPS]
I was in a really rough fight.
You did it again, moron!
How could you treat my precious automail like that, Alchemy Freak?!
Uh, are you there?
Hello, Winry.
Guess I've got no choice.
Tell me how to get there.
ED: You're sure in a good mood today.
I thought you were going to—you know what? Never mind. Forget it.
Yeah.
Yep.
Sorry again, and thanks.
Right.
Goodbye.
[EXHALES]
Aw, was that your girlfriend?
My girlfriend?! No way!
It's nothing to be embarrassed about.
When I was your age, I had a
different girlfriend every week.
Hmm?
What are you doing sitting
there in the dark by yourself?
Hey.
Hey,  Al.
Brother.
You know you can come to the room, right?
I'll be there in a little while.
You go on ahead.
Okay.
[SOFT, MECHANICAL FOOTSTEPS]
[GIGGLE]
Bye!
Are you sure you're not a puppet
created by your so-called brother?
[BELLS RINGING]
Ugh, that left me really sore.
I don't understand how Ed
and Al can ride on these things.
Ed said to look near the west exit.
There'd be someone familiar there
who I'd recognize right away.
Hello, Major Armstrong, it's Winry!
Hello, Miss Winry. Did you have a pleasant trip?
Where are those stupid Elric brothers?
[GULPS]
Well, you see...
Hmm?
[INDISCERNIBLE]
The hospital? What happened?!
ED: Well, that didn't take long.
You're gonna charge me an
express service fee now, aren't you?
No, I... I won't
charge you for this.
I didn't do a good enough job on your automail last time.
And now you're badly injured.
It's not your fault! You can't blame yourself for this!
I broke it because I was being reckless!
Your repairs were flawless as ever! This was all my fault!
WINRY: He has no idea...
He never noticed that I
forgot to put in that screw.
Besides, if my arm hadn't
broken when it did, I would have
kept fighting and then I would
have been hurt even worse!
So don't worry about it, okay?
Okay?
WINRY: So it turned out all right?
[LAUGHS]
Well, then, let's go ahead and get right down to business, shall we?
I'll have to charge you the
usual rush order fee, of course.
Huh?
Hmm?
You didn't drink your milk.
Why should I?
I hate it.
You're going to be small and stunted
forever if you keep using that stupid excuse!
Shut up!
I don't have to drink it if I don't wanna!
You sound like a spoiled little brat, Edward Elric!
ROSS: Every growing boy needs his milk.
BROSH: Yeah, you want the girls to like ya, don't you?
- Was that Al?
- Hmm?
ED: I don't get it.
Al's been acting really weird lately.
WINRY: Weird how?
Just seems like something's
been bothering him.
Are you sure you're not a puppet
created by your so-called brother?
Just accept it.
You'll feel better.
[MIRROR CRACKS]
WINRY: Okay! You're all set.
[GROANS] Well done!
Ah, it feels good to have it back.
Wow, thanks a lot.
Sure, no problem.
[DOOR OPENS]
Hm?
Yo, Ed, my boy!
Is it true you brought a pretty blonde
girl into your room to service you?
She's my automail mechanic, that's all! Nothing more!
Oh, I see.
You've seduced your mechanic, have you?
[SCREAMS]
That isn't what I said at all! Were you even listening to me?!
Maes Hughes, I'm pleased
to meet you, young lady.
You too, I'm Winry Rockbell.
Nice to see you, Hughes.
But don't you have work to do?
Nope, it's all under control.
I gave Sheska some overtime.
ED: You're a real jerk, aren't you?
Oh, yeah, and I think you'll be happy to know...
I just found out you and Al shouldn't need to be kept
under guard for too much longer.
ED: Great!
WINRY: What'd you say?
Hold on just a second!
How much trouble have you
gotten yourself into this time?
Uh, well, you see, it's...
Well, it's nothing that concerns you.
Of course not.
I don't know why I bother to try.
It's not like you'll talk to me anyway.
Fine, I'll see you tomorrow.
I have to go and see if I
can find some place to stay tonight.
Come on, no need for that. Why don't you spend the night at my place?
Really?
Yes, of course.
My wife and daughter will
be delighted to have you.
- Oh no, I—
- It's settled. Come on, come on.
Here, let me take that.
Oh, I've got it! Let's go!
- Do you really have to drag me?
- [LAUGHING]
[POPPING]
[LAUGHTER]
Happy birthday, Elicia!
[CHEERING]
Um, you don't mind me asking, Mr. Hughes, what is this all about?
I'm so glad you asked that, Miss Winry.
Today happens to be my
darling little Elicia's birthday!
Yeah, my birthday!
[LAUGHING]
That's exciting.
How old are you now, Elicia?
I'm two!
No, I'm three!
Oh how adorable!
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Fullmetal Alchemist
I've known the Elrics for about
as long as I can remember.
We grew up together.
They're like my brothers.
And I'm sure knowing those two,
they must give you plenty to worry about.
That's an understatement.
When they finally came back for a visit, it
was because Ed's arm was all busted up.
And now he calls me out here because
he's been seriously injured again.
Something's bothering Al, too.
They keep their mouths shut, though.
They don't ever tell me what's going on.
It's just like when they left
Resembool for the first time.
HUGHES: Maybe nothing needed to be said.
You know these boys, Winry.
It's possible they thought you'd
understand without them saying anything.
Maybe.
But there are some things
that I actually need to be told.
Just what am I going to do with you?
In general, men prefer to let their
actions speak instead of words.
When they're in pain, they don't
want to burden anyone with it.
Not if they can help it.
They don't want anyone to worry about them.
That's how they are.
Even so, there may come a
time when they'll ask for your help.
And when they do, I know
that you'll be there for them.
Isn't that enough?
Elicia, we wanna play! Let's go!
Will you put me down now?
WINRY: Okay, down you go.
Hey, you get away from her!
Elicia wants to play with me, not you!
She's quite the heartbreaker
already, isn't she?
[GUN COCKING]
Listen up, boys.
You try anything with my
daughter, and you will answer to me.
Your actions speak too loudly!
GRACIA: Are you sure you have to go?
You're more than welcome to stay
with us for as long as you're in town.
I don't want to put you out
more than I have already.
Elicia's gotten very attached to you.
[LAUGHS]
Well, would you look at that!
The two of you could be sisters.
Sissy! Be safe, okay?
And come back and visit me real soon!
It's settled.
You're staying with us again tonight.
[BOTH GIGGLING]
It looks like I found
myself a little sister.
So we meet again, you little bastard.
I'm not gonna drink you.
Brother, you have a living
body that needs nourishment.
You have to drink it.
I don't have to if I don't want to.
It may not look like it, but I have grown some.
But everyone still calls me a pipsqueak.
I wish I was like you, Al.
You've got such a big body now.
It's not like I asked
for this body, brother!
Sorry. You're right.
It's my fault that it happened.
But I'll make it right. I'll get you
back into your real body. You'll see, Al.
AL: That's what you always say,
but you don't know that for sure!
L-look, I promise I'm gonna get you back.
Believe me, Al. I'll do it.
Believe you?
How am I supposed to believe
anything when I'm stuck in this body?
What should I believe in? My memories?
Memories are just scraps of information that
can be made up as easily as anything else.
Al, what are you talking about?
Do you remember when you said there
was something you were afraid to tell me?
I think...
I think I might know what it was.
Maybe you wanted to say that my soul and my memories
are really artificial constructions you created!
You... Winry and Granny... You've
been lying to me all along, haven't you?
What do you have to
say for yourself, brother?
ED: Is that what you really think?
Have you believed that all this time?
[GASP]
So, are you finished?
Or is there more you wanted to say?
Okay.
Don't go.
Ed!
WINRY: Al, you...
...Moron!
[CLANG]
ALL: Ah!
Where did that come from?!
[PANTING]
[GASPS] Winry?!
You idiot!
[CLANG]
You have no idea how Ed feels!
Do you know what he was
so afraid to talk to you about?
He wants to know if you blame him
for what happened to your body, Al!
It's all my fault.
Al lost his body and it's all my fault.
He can't eat anymore, he can't
sleep, he can't feel cold or warm.
He's my little brother and I'm supposed to protect him
and I did this and—[SOBBING]
How could he ever forgive me?
Al isn't the type of boy who would resent you for this.
Just ask him and I'm sure you'll see.
No. I'm... I'm too afraid.
I'm too scared of what he'll say.
[CLANGING]
And then... you idiot! You said that!
Whoever'd do something like that?
Who would be prepared to risk his own
life to create a fake brother?
Don't you get it? [SNIFFLES]
All the two of you have left... is each other.
Now! Go get your brother!
- Start running!
- Right!
- Bro—
- You know something, Al?
We haven't had a good fight in a while.
I'm starting to get flabby.
Huh?
Huh? Hey!
Hold on, brother!
Stop!
Your wounds haven't healed enough for this!
I beat you! The first time I ever won!
It wasn't a fair fight, brother.
Don't give me that.
A win is a win and you know it, Al.
We've always fought like this.
Ever since we were really little.
Now that I think about it, we've fought
over some really stupid things, haven't we?
Definitely. Like who would
get the top and bottom bunks.
Yeah.
AL: We fought over candy a lot too, huh?
ED: And that toy, you remember?
AL: I won that one.
And when we played in the rain river too.
ED: Oh yeah. You shoved me into the water.
AL: And that fight we had during our training?
ED: Teacher said we were
being too loud, then she beat
us up herself. Why don't
we call that one a draw?
AL: We even fought over which one
of us would marry Winry someday.
ED: What?! I don't remember that one.
AL: I won the fight, but she shot me down.
ED: Oh...did she?
You're telling me that all
those memories are lies?
AL: Sorry.
ED: And your determination to be whole again
to get your body back no matter what...
That's a lie too?
AL: No, it's not a lie.
ED: That's Right
We're in this together, all the way.
And forget that, we're
gonna keep pushing forward.
We'll make ourselves stronger, faster,
and better until we get our bodies back.
[AL CHUCKLES] And the milk?
ED: Milk?! Fine. I'll drink...a little.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
ED: Whatever it takes, brother.
AL: Mm!
Mr. Hughes?
Maybe you don't have to hear something out loud,
but it sure is helpful sometimes.
I guess it is.
My brother...
Master...
They're gone. All gone.
Hey!
You don't look like an Ishvalan.
Who are you?
KIMBLEE: Oh my, where are my manners?
I should have introduced myself.
I'm a State Alchemist
sent here by the military.
I've been sent to
exterminate this sector.
Hey, you're awake!
Where am I?
In a slum outside of East City.
You're among friends now.
Who are you? You, old man.
Me? Why, I'm a man of
Ishvala, just as you are, son.
There's nothing to worry about here.
I won't sell out one of my own.
Are we the only ones here?
Are there other Ishvalan survivors?
Yes, indeed there are.
A run-down slum such as this may
bear no resemblance to our ancestral home,
But you know what they
say, the world is God's bosom.
Our great, loving God Ishvala. Am I right? [CHUCKLES]
Yes, you certainly are.
You can't, you're not ready!
We found you
floating in the sewers. You were hurt bad.
Boy, my right arm.
Did I lose it or is it still with me?
Yeah, it's still there, mister.
It should be fine.
Your tattoo...it's really amazing.
Yes, it's important to me.
A precious gift from my family.
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee kimi wa oboete imasu ka
Yakusoku chigiri shoka
no kaze ga tsutsumu
futari yorisotta
Muri na egao no ura
nobita kage o kakumau
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei o erabu
Table no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
kuuhaku no yoru o kuru hazu no nai asa mo
zenbu wakatte'tan da
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
Hatasenakatta yakusoku o idaite
futari arukidasu
A good friend became
a comrade-in-arms,
and over time, his presence was taken for granted.
Although the future they once dreamed of
became bleaker than they had ever imagined,
this good friend was always there
by his side, where he belonged.
Next time on Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood
Episode 10: Separate Destinations.
A friend whose presence comes as naturally
as breathing can never be replaced.